<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<ws>
    <settings>
        <stage width="880px" height="480px" id="Stage" create="yes" center="yes" />
        <triggers>
            <trigger name="next_by_right" event="keyup" key="RIGHT_ARROW" special="next" />
        </triggers>
    </settings>
    <assets>
        <textbox name="tb_main" behaviour="adv" cssid="MainTb" names="yes" 
            x="8px" y="368px" width="860px" height="100px"></textbox>
            
        <textbox name="tb_credits" behaviour="adv" cssid="CreditsTb" names="no" 
            x="5px" y="5px" z="1000" width="870px" height="470px"></textbox>
            
        <character name="h" textbox="tb_main">
            <displayname>Heir</displayname>
        </character>
        
        <character name="n" textbox="tb_credits"></character>
        
        <imagepack name="img_heir" x="100px" y="-200px" z="5">
            <image src="assets/images/heir28.jpg" name="skeptical_eo_mo" />
            <image src="assets/images/heir29.jpg" name="neutral_eo_mo" />
            <image src="assets/images/heir30.jpg" name="neutral_el_mo" />
            <image src="assets/images/heir31.jpg" name="neutral_er_mo" />
            <image src="assets/images/heir32.jpg" name="surprised_eo_mo" />
            <image src="assets/images/heir4.jpg" name="annoyed_ec_mo" />
        </imagepack>
    </assets>
    <scenes>
        <scene id="start">
            
            <trigger name="next_by_right" action="activate" />
            
            
            <show asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="right" />
            
            <line s="n">
                {img src="/images/webstory-engine-logo-medium" alt="logo" style="margin-top: -50px;" /}{br /}
                Please click on the screen to start.{br /}
                Inside the story, you can also press the {b}RIGHT ARROW{/b} key to go to the next line.
            </line>
            
            <hide asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="right" />
            <wait />
            
            <set asset="img_heir" image="neutral_eo_mo" duration="0" />
            <wait />
            <show asset="img_heir" duration="500" effect="slide" direction="bottom" easing="easeOutBounce" />
            <wait />
            <set asset="img_heir" image="neutral_el_mo" duration="300" />
            <wait />
            <set asset="img_heir" image="neutral_er_mo" duration="300" />
            <wait />
            <set asset="img_heir" image="neutral_eo_mo" duration="300" />
            <wait />
            <show asset="tb_main" effect="slide" direction="top" />
            
            <line s="h">
                Good afternoon. My assistant Lia has been blackmailing me into giving you folks
                a quick introduction of the visual novel engine we're using: the WebStory Engine.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                My name is Heir, by the way, and I'm the boss of a largely unsuccessful
                visual novel studio.
            </line>
            
            <set asset="img_heir" image="surprised_eo_mo" duration="500" />
            
            <line s="h">
                What do you mean, 'funny'?
            </line>
            
            <set asset="img_heir" image="annoyed_ec_mo" duration="500" />
            
            <line s="h">
                It's not a joke! It's my name! My name, ok?!
            </line>
            
            <set asset="img_heir" image="skeptical_eo_mo" duration="200" />
            
            <line s="h">
                And I happen to like it, you know.
            </line>
            
            <set asset="img_heir" image="neutral_eo_mo" duration="200" />
            
            <line s="h">
                So, what's your name, huh?
            </line>
            
            <prompt title="Enter your name" message="Please enter your name!" var="players_name" />
            
            <var name="players_name" action="print" />
            
            <var ifvar="players_name" ifvalue="null" name="players_name" value="[anonymous]" />
            <var ifvar="players_name" ifvalue="" name="players_name" value="[anonymous]" />
            
            <var name="players_name" action="print" />
            
            <line s="h" ifvar="players_name" ifvalue="[anonymous]">
                Yeah, I figured as much: too afraid to give me your name because it's just THAT ugly.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h" ifvar="players_name" ifnot="[anonymous]">
                {$players_name}? Really? Wow, that's a pretty ugly name you got there. No wonder
                that you feel the urge to make fun of other people's names then, I suppose.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Well, names aside, let's talk about the engine.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                The WebStory Engine is an engine for web-based story games, that is, visual novels.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                I guess you DO at least know what a visual novel is, don't you?
            </line>
            
            <choice>
                <option label="Sure, I know what that is.">
                    <var name="knows_visual_novels" value="true" />
                </option>
                <option label="Well, uh... not really.">
                    <var name="knows_visual_novels" value="false" />
                </option>
            </choice>
            
            <sub ifvar="knows_visual_novels" ifvalue="false" scene="explain_vn" />
            
            <goto scene="explain_wse" />
        </scene>
        
        
        <scene id="explain_wse">
            
            <line s="h">
                With that embarrassing question out of the way, let's talk about what
                the WebStory Engine can do for you.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                First of all, it is called WEBStory Engine for a reason. And that is:
                Games made with the engine can be played on normal websites.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                The player does not need to install anything on their computer.
                That's a HUGE plus compared to traditional games, let me tell you that.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                And the engine does not use any proprietary browser plugins like flash.
                Every modern browser should be able to play games made using the engine.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Stories written with the engine are called WebStories by the way.
                That is because they don't have to be visual novels, although making VNs
                is the main purpose of the software.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                WebStories are written in a rather easy-to-understand language.
                You don't need to be a programmer to use it.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Although this one does not have any music, your WebStories can have that, of
                course.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                If you want to make some more sophisticated visual novels than just
                text with some decision points, the engine lets you define variables and
                you can do advanced branching using sub routines and 
                (eww, gross) gotos.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                You can freely define which keyboard keys a user should hit to get to the next
                line.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                The engine has a built-in savegame system that lets the player save the state of
                the VN on any line, should you as a developer choose to enable that feature.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                You can also define some simple animations using the engine.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                The WebStory Engine is free open source software. That means you can use it for free,
                redistribute it, change it and do commercial games with it. 
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Heck, you could even take the whole thing, put your logo
                on it and sell it for horrendous prices, should you suddenly feel like
                ripping off the poor guy that developed it.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Well, as you can see, the engine has a lot to offer. There are too many features in it
                to mention them all here. Besides, this stupid introduction took enough of my precious time already.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                With that, I'm outta here, scratching my hairy butt or something. See you.
            </line>
            
            <goto scene="restart" />
        </scene>
        
        
        <scene id="explain_vn">
            
            <set asset="img_heir" image="surprised_eo_mo" duration="300" />
            
            <line s="h">
                I don't believe you. Do you live under some rock or what?
            </line>
            
            <set asset="img_heir" image="neutral_eo_mo" duration="300" />
            
            <line s="h">
                A visual novel is basically a story that is played on a computer
                or other kind of electronic device that has images and sounds
                to enrich the experience. Like what you are looking at now.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Well, calling it a story is one way to look at it. Some people
                might argue that VNs are games and not really {em}novels{/em}.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Some visual novels even feature voices or include some mini games.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Most visual novels let the player influence the outcome of the story
                by asking her from time to time what the protagonist should be doing next.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Visual novels are a big hit in Japan, but more and more people outside
                of the country take an interest in visual novels.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                There are both professional games being made in the genre as well as a lot
                of indie and hobbyist works.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                If you want to play some good free visual novels, google for Narcissu,
                Katawa Shoujo, Adrift or Ripples.
            </line>
            
            <line s="h">
                Well, I guess that's enough of an explanation for now.
            </line>
            
        </scene>
        
        
        <scene id="restart">
            
            <hide asset="img_heir" effect="fade" />
            <hide asset="tb_main" effect="fade" />
            
            <wait />
            
            <show asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="right" />
            
            <line s="n">
                {img src="/images/webstory-engine-logo-medium" alt="logo" /}
            </line>
            
            <hide asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="right" />
            <wait />
            <show asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="right" />
            
            <line s="n">
                {b}Offensive Plot &amp; Programming:{/b}{br /}
                C7N
            </line>
            
            <hide asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="right" />
            <wait />
            <show asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="right" />
            
            <line s="n">
                {b}Awesome Character Art:{/b}{br /}
                {a onclick="window.open(this.href); return false;" href="http://anemontaglub.deviantart.com/"}anemonta{/a}
            </line>
            
            <hide asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="right" />
            <wait />
            <show asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="bottom" easing="easeOutBounce" />
            
            <line s="n">
                The images used in this game are copyrighted, please don't steal them. Thank you.
            </line>
            
            <hide asset="tb_credits" effect="slide" direction="bottom" />
            
            <trigger name="next_by_right" action="deactivate" />
            <trigger name="next_by_space" action="deactivate" />
            <wait />
            <restart />
        </scene>
    </scenes>
</ws>